World War III.
By 2036,
it will have resulted in 5.7 billion casualties worldwide.
And this is what starts it.
Huh? What is it?
It's some kind of robot?
Does it transform and stuff?
A time machine.
Seriously?
I knew you'd recognize it, Uncle.
Then that makes this easy.
Come with me.
I refuse.
Okarin?
I came here from the Alpha worldline.
Over the past three weeks,
I jumped worldlines again and again,
sacrificing Kurisu in order to return to the Beta worldline.
I won't let it all be for naught!
Kurisu?
Wasn't that the name of the scientist
who was stabbed at the Radio Kaikan?
Okabe Rintarou,
what if I told you that the way to avoid World War III
is, on July 28th, 2010,
to prevent Makise Kurisu's death?
What do you mean?
I don't know the details,
but I have one mission:
To save Makise Kurisu
and to go to the one worldline
unaffected by the attractor field,
the Steins Gate!
Claims of life and meaningless proofs
inochi no shuchou to muimi no shoumei
anata ni wa taikutsu shinogi ni taranu koukei
are not enough to amuse you
shihaisha kidori no orokana shuzoku wa
Acting as the leader of a foolish group
unuboreta chisetsuna teiri wo narabeta
you lay down childish theories
mugen to shinjita ai mo sora no kanata mo
Infinite love and the distant sky
bokutachi ni shimesareta kasou no jiyuu
are but virtual liberties shown to us
yuugen sore wa mujihi ni toki wo kizami
Finitude is the merciless passage of time
asu sae mo hitei suru sentaku e
as I head towards my choice to deny even tomorrow
Hacking to the Gate
ikutsu mo no kagayakeru hibi nakama to no yakusoku
I must never break the promise to my friends
nakatta koto ni wa shite wa ikenai
of the shining days we would be together
sono tame ni toki wo azamuku nokosareta shikake ni
For that is why I deceive time with the tricks I am left with
mou mayoi wa nai kodoku no kansokusha
I no longer have any hesitations, the lone observer
Open the
Missing Link
Steins Gate?
The architects of this plan were
my father and your future self.
None of it is more than a hypothesis.
It's possible for the theory to be wrong,
for there to be no Steins Gate worldline,
but I'm going regardless.
I'll bet on the chance that a shining future's waiting for me.
If you're coming with me,
then take my hand.
Um,
Mayushii didn't really understand any of that,
but if this person,
this Kurisu, is important to you,
shouldn't you try to help her?
World War III sounds like one of your crazy delusions.
No one else could handle it.
I don't care about the 5.7 billion people in the future...
but...
Thank you.
Let's go.
Two people can get in it?
Of course!
This is my dad's masterpiece.
Okarin!
Leave your phone.
It might interfere with your phone in the past.
I'll be back.
Good luck.
This is a time machine.
Yeah,
I stopped in 1975 and 2000.
It's working fine,
but it's running out of fuel.
Wait. It can go from past to future?
Of course it can.
It's a time machine.
I see.
Is that because we're in a different worldline now?
Sit down.
We'll head to just before noon on July 28th.
We can't change location,
so if we arrive too early, it'll spread panic at the Radio Kaikan,
possibly affecting Makise Kurisu's actions.
Your first time, the Gs are pretty tough.
Get ready.
Okarin...
What is this?
These always show up.
I guess they're like fragments of time.
Pretty, huh?
Let's go!
W-Wait.
I think I'm going to throw up.
What a wimp.
Hurry!
Don't let your other self see you.
It'll cause a serious time paradox.
How long until the stabbing?
Twenty minutes or so, I guess.
I'll prepare the time machine.
You protect her, Uncle.
Stop calling me that.
July 28th.
On the day I saw Kurisu lying in a pool of blood,
I came with Mayuri to see
Doctor Nakabachi's press conference.
I heard a noise on the roof.
That's right. After that, Mayuri went to the seventh-floor Upa machines.
Oh, no!
You called me here for this?
There aren't many left of this series, and Mayushii's...
Oh well.
I'll take the back stairs to the eighth floor.
It's a metal... a metal Upa!
Is it rare?
Extremely!
Now that I'm here...
I'm sorry.
K-Kurisu?
H-How do you know my name?
Kurisu is alive.
Have we met somewhere?
Kurisu...
Are you listening—
What's wrong?
Answer me.
I...
I'm... trying...
Doctor Nakabachi's press conference in Hall 8 will be opening now.
Wait!
Wait a second!
In the handouts, you can read about the time machine's basic design.
Doctor Nakabachi's Time Machine Invention Press Conference
I will use this conference as an opportunity to discuss the fundamental theory behind it.
Doctor Nakabachi
The operation notes said that you'd be able to identify Makise Kurisu.
Can you?
Yeah.
Also, it's dangerous to take her outside.
If we don't figure out who stabbed her,
we can't change her fate.
Just like Mayuri?
Doctor!
What is it?
You know exactly what!
What is this "time machine theory" of yours?
Kerr Black Holes?
World lines?
You stole all of this from John Titor!
Kurisu will be stabbed right here soon.
Is she really going to be here?
Wait! Maybe she was stabbed elsewhere and brought here.
Yeah... That's possible!
Kurisu?
So it does happen here.
What's she reading?
A time machine?
Is that why she's the key to changing worldlines?
What do you want?
Daddy, I wanted you to read this.
Daddy?
Doctor Nakabachi?
You contacted me for the first time in seven years.
You asked me to come to your press conference, right?
That was my inspiration.
Wait. So Kurisu's dad is...
So I thought I could use it to theorize a time machine.
I wanted to hear your ideas.
If this is accepted, you can use it
as revenge for everyone who kicked you out—
I wasn't kicked out!
I got sick of them and left.
Sorry.
It's not bad.
Really?
If you're okay with it,
I thought we could put both of our names on the paper
because you inspired me—
Don't be stupid.
Leave!
I'll publish this paper under my name.
Wait!
You wouldn't steal it, right, Daddy?
I never thought you'd resort to tha—
Shut up!
How dare you call it stealing?!
Why are you so smart?
A girl shouldn't be smarter than her father!
If it weren't for you, I would've been considered smart!
If it weren't for you...
You're that kid from earlier.
So that's it?
You were plotting to ruin my conference together, huh?
I see.
So that's it.
Daddy!
I'll protect her!
How dare you insult me?
Why, you...
Stop it, Daddy!
Please!
Don't even speak to me!
Oh, shit!
What do you know?
You don't know how I feel.
You don't know how I've been humiliated
and the hell I've been through!
Papa...
If it weren't for you...
Don't...
Don't do it!
Kurisu...
K-Kurisu!
Fools.
This is the perfect end for you.
I'm sorry for getting you involved.
Why?
Because he's my dad,
I wanted him to accept me.
That's all.
Kurisu...
I'm scared...
I... I don't want to die.
I don't want to die.
I don't...
Kurisu...
Kurisu!
They're back already!
Okarin!
Okarin, that blood...
It's all right.
It isn't his.
I was the one who killed Kurisu.
Okarin?
I know it hurts, but you can't give up yet.
We have enough fuel to go back one more time.
Shut up!
Nothing will change!
The attractor field convergence will kill her all over again.
All... All of it...
It's all my fault...
5.7 billion lives hang in the balance!
You have to save Makise Kurisu and change the World Line!
It's impossible...
Why?
It was just one failure!
Just one...?
Don't give me that shit!
Just how many times do you think I failed?
Just how many dozens of times do you think I failed?
I know how this will go...
And how absurd this whole thing is...
I'm well aware of the cruel ending that awaits...
I knew...
I knew this would happen...
I'm tired...
I'm so tired...
If that's how you want to be, I'll have to slap some sense into you—
Stop!
You shouldn't force him.
But there's no way he can change the future like this!
Why? Why are you making Okarin shoulder the future by himself?
That's too big a burden.
Uncle Okarin is the only one who can observe the worldlines.
Okarin never asked for that.
And even if you tell him to try one more time, he'll just get hurt again.
Thinking one person alone can change the future... That just isn't possible.
Kuri...su... Kurisu... Kuri...
Hey, Okarin...
You don't have to struggle anymore.
It's okay to cry, Okarin.
Mayushii is here with you.
The cicadas are all gone now.
Been a while since we've been to this park too.
Okarin's been pretty busy since summer vacation ended, after all.
I went to my first mixer recently, y'know.
Is that right?
Speaking of.
Hello.
Oh, what's going on?
Tomorrow? That's pretty sudden.
I'm sure I'd just be there to even the numbers out.
Why not? I'll go.
Later.
I never expected college life to be this busy.
Mayushii...
Mayushii is so happy to see Okarin again after so long.
Hey, Okarin.
Why don't you stop by the lab?
You haven't visited for a while, so it's been really quiet...
Alright.
Then it's settled, Okarin.
Yeah. Well, see you later.
Yep!
Mayuri is safely here with us.
Not this town... Not myself... Nothing at all... has changed.
kisei sareta shikai mujihi naru
With my field of view restricted
juuni no shihai nogarerarenai
I cannot escape the merciless control of the twelve
ansoku no asu wo negatta
While wishing for a tomorrow of repose
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei he
I headed for the sacred event horizon in my hand
toraware shi meiyaku arawareta gishou no rinkaku
Pledges are imprisoned, and false evidences are showing their outline
seimei no tenchi wa moumoku na jikan wo kizanda
This world of life blindly lets the time pass by
habatake butterfly
Spread your wings
kiseki no butterfly
butterfly of miracles
anata he sasagu
I dedicate it to you
namida no butterfly
Oh butterfly of tears
mabushii butterfly
butterfly of radiance
subete ga ima kakikaerareru
everything will now be rewritten
Nice to meet you. I'm Makise Kurisu.
I hope we can get along.
It seems fate has decided to converge once again, Hououin Kyouma.
I guess I have to fight either way in the end. Pray for my good fortune.
El Psy Kongroo.